<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Marat&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://kopytjuk.github.io/kopytjuk/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Marat&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 11:19:40 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kopytjuk.github.io/kopytjuk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wrap C&#43;&#43; algorithms in Python for pre-production evaluation and experimentation.</title>
      <link>https://kopytjuk.github.io/kopytjuk/posts/wrapping-cpp-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 11:19:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kopytjuk.github.io/kopytjuk/posts/wrapping-cpp-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>TLDR; In model based design paradigm one often implements a proof-of-concept solution in a scripting language before porting the logic to a more performant low-level language like C/C++. This article describes the benefits of calling production-ready (C/C++) ports in Python for functional evaluation and analysis. Assessment tools developed previously during the experimentation stage can be reused. Furthermore, the complexity for experimentation with various internal parameters is reduced, which can optimize costs and expensive debugging prior to the final deployment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://kopytjuk.github.io/kopytjuk/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kopytjuk.github.io/kopytjuk/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Marat, I am born in the early 90&amp;rsquo;s, work and live in Heilbronn (South Germany). I was born in Belarus, got my mechatronics degree in Germany. My mother language is Russian, but over the time the available vocabulary in German and English got more advanced.
I count myself as an interdisciplinary developer who believes that combining cross-domain expertise in mechatronical systems, robotics, software engineering, cloud and probability theory is essential towards inspiring, efficient, future-proof and reliable products.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
